davidgurulejr@gmail.com · MONUMENT, CO 80921 · 719-251-5984 · linkedin www.david-barclav-gurule.com

DAVID BARCLAY GURULE JR

WEB DEVELOPER | SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL-STACK

SKILLS

REACT, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, Express, PostgreSQL, Flexbox, Postman, AirTable, MongoDB, Linux, Windows, Nextjs, Firebase

WHO AM I?

Hi, my name is David and I am a graduate from General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp. I also hold a Masters in Management and a Bachelors in Sociology. I love to learn. For most of my adult life I have dedicated my time to helping others. I spent 15 years in law enforcement, with five years of that time in a project management role. I spent my last year in law enforcement supervising a team of highly energetic and motivated members. My passion is for people, innovation, technology and how they support each other. I am enthusiastic about projects where I am coding to benefit others in meaningful ways.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Colorado Springs, Colorado December 2021-Current

Since graduating I have continued online courses in Computer Science, JS, OOP, React, & PostgreSQL. I have worked with two teams building projects. I have a strong passion for learning and I am looking for a good fit with an organization.

General Assembly Student

New York, New York September 2021-December 2021

With General Assembly I received experience in both frontend and backend systems and completed projects demonstrating not just code knowledge but the processes involved in the full project life-cycle. We learned modern frameworks and I have experience in wire-framing, pseudocoding, diagramming and planning. Here are some of the projects I worked on: https://hekates-bees.netlify.app/ https://everfree-outdoors.netlify.app/

Colorado State Patrol Sergeant, Trooper, Recruiter, Registrar

Lakewood, Colorado January 2007-September 2021

With the Colorado State Patrol I contributed in several leadership roles while serving the citizens of Colorado and keeping our great State safe. I was awarded for several contributions: top DUI, seatbelts, top academics, etc. I have leadership experience with fast-paced high risk situations i.e. stand-offs, shootings, fatal and serious injury crashes, use-of-force reporting, etc.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Software Engineer Program

New York, New York

September 2021-December 2021

I completed a twelve week immersion program which included project experience and tools and languages including but not limited to: HTML, CSS, JS, API's, React, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, Ruby on Rails, Postgres

Colorado State University

Master's Degree - Management - GPA 3.8

Greenwood Village, Colorado May 2014-March 2017

I completed a MS degree in Management which consisted of strategic planning, quantitative and qualitative methodology, critical thinking, economics and project management.

Colorado State University - Pueblo Bachelor's Degree - Sociology - GPA 3.9

Pueblo, Colorado August 2003 - December 2005

I completed a 4 year degree with an emphasis in Criminology. I completed internships with a district attorney's office and a sheriff's department. I graduated Summa Cum Laude.